<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-31T06:47:18+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jojo Siao Blog</title><subtitle>Jojo Siao Blog</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Starting New Role As Rails Developer</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/10/starting_new_role_as_rails_dev.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting New Role As Rails Developer" /><published>2019-10-05T08:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-05T08:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/10/starting_new_role_as_rails_dev</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/10/starting_new_role_as_rails_dev.html">&lt;p&gt;This coming November, I will be working in a different company as a Rails Developer,
and I am so excited about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really hard to leave my current employer, after more than two years of working there. 
I really felt like they were my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I start to work in my new company, they want me to study ruby basics, gems, and rails 
basics as well. Funny thing is, this blog is created using jekyll gem. That means I 
have a bit of background in ruby.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This coming November, I will be working in a different company as a Rails Developer, and I am so excited about it. It was really hard to leave my current employer, after more than two years of working there. I really felt like they were my family. Before I start to work in my new company, they want me to study ruby basics, gems, and rails basics as well. Funny thing is, this blog is created using jekyll gem. That means I have a bit of background in ruby.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Panalo na, Natalo pa</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/09/panalo-na-natalo-pa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Panalo na, Natalo pa" /><published>2019-09-23T08:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-09-23T08:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/09/panalo-na-natalo-pa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/09/panalo-na-natalo-pa.html">&lt;p&gt;Forgive me to use Filipino words to give a title 
for this blog. Honestly, I’ve been googling for 
a translation of this in english but I couldn’t find
anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think you are familiar with this scenario.
Let’s say you are playing in a chess tournament,
and you have a winning advantage and you can
simplify your play to an endgame. But you committed
ONE simple blunder, and that made you lose the game 
instead in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is just the same at work. When you know for yourself that
you are doing great in your work, but then you make one simple
mistake and it blows up everything else into more complicated issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that’s the reason why some of us would come up with the idea
and make it a life decision to live a simple life. 
A definition of a simple life is living your 
whole life avoiding troubles or misunderstandings with others.
You could also say that a simple life is to live self-sufficiently. 
But this could also mean living your life avoiding risks and challenges.
Because it is part of life to encounter troubles; it’s just 
not right to say that to live a simple life will be problem-free.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Forgive me to use Filipino words to give a title for this blog. Honestly, I’ve been googling for a translation of this in english but I couldn’t find anywhere. But I think you are familiar with this scenario. Let’s say you are playing in a chess tournament, and you have a winning advantage and you can simplify your play to an endgame. But you committed ONE simple blunder, and that made you lose the game instead in the end. It is just the same at work. When you know for yourself that you are doing great in your work, but then you make one simple mistake and it blows up everything else into more complicated issues. Maybe that’s the reason why some of us would come up with the idea and make it a life decision to live a simple life. A definition of a simple life is living your whole life avoiding troubles or misunderstandings with others. You could also say that a simple life is to live self-sufficiently. But this could also mean living your life avoiding risks and challenges. Because it is part of life to encounter troubles; it’s just not right to say that to live a simple life will be problem-free.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Battling Depression</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/09/battling-depression.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Battling Depression" /><published>2019-09-18T08:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-09-18T08:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/09/battling-depression</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/09/battling-depression.html">&lt;p&gt;I just recently consulted a doctor and the doctor’s impression on me is
that I have major depression, sleep apnea, high blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now knowing that I am suffering from depression, I had a realization that 
most of the pain I am suffering from could be hallucination or imaginary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to confirm it for myself if I am really suffering from depression, 
so I am going to consult a psychiatrist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this blog post to inform anyone whoever reads this. If someone 
in your family discloses that he or she is suffering from depression, 
please let him or her to understand that he or she is not alone.
The person needs more support now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I just recently consulted a doctor and the doctor’s impression on me is that I have major depression, sleep apnea, high blood pressure. Now knowing that I am suffering from depression, I had a realization that most of the pain I am suffering from could be hallucination or imaginary. I want to confirm it for myself if I am really suffering from depression, so I am going to consult a psychiatrist. I am writing this blog post to inform anyone whoever reads this. If someone in your family discloses that he or she is suffering from depression, please let him or her to understand that he or she is not alone. The person needs more support now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Going Back To Blogging Again</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/05/going-back-to-blogging-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Going Back To Blogging Again" /><published>2019-05-23T11:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-05-23T11:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/05/going-back-to-blogging-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/05/going-back-to-blogging-again.html">&lt;p&gt;Blogging is like a therapy for me because it enables me to communicate my
thoughts well as if I am talking to a live person and it also helps me to 
organize my thoughts and ideas and let me say everything in the right process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am again, I am back to be blogging again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my purpose of making blog posts was to remind myself in the future the
lessons I learned and experience I gained from those lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning to make vlogs as well. I watched some youtubers on how they 
make their vlogs. I bought the fisheye lens from CDR King. I also just recently 
purchased a mic for a mobile phone from Amazon. I hope the package will
arrive soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cutting this blog post short. Peace to all. And God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Blogging is like a therapy for me because it enables me to communicate my thoughts well as if I am talking to a live person and it also helps me to organize my thoughts and ideas and let me say everything in the right process. So here I am again, I am back to be blogging again. But my purpose of making blog posts was to remind myself in the future the lessons I learned and experience I gained from those lessons. I am planning to make vlogs as well. I watched some youtubers on how they make their vlogs. I bought the fisheye lens from CDR King. I also just recently purchased a mic for a mobile phone from Amazon. I hope the package will arrive soon. cutting this blog post short. Peace to all. And God bless.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Youtube TED/TEDx talks</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/03/youtube-motivational-videos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Youtube TED/TEDx talks" /><published>2019-03-16T11:04:26+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-16T11:04:26+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/03/youtube-motivational-videos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/03/youtube-motivational-videos.html">&lt;p&gt;Hope these links from youtube can help you become motivated in whatever you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/3zJHwOwirjA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/5pW2b1vwwf4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/BT2XlI8oeh0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/ZQNk7KVU_6A&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hope these links from youtube can help you become motivated in whatever you do. https://youtu.be/3zJHwOwirjA https://youtu.be/5pW2b1vwwf4 https://youtu.be/BT2XlI8oeh0 https://youtu.be/ZQNk7KVU_6A</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weird Dream, Lost A Shoe</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/03/weird-dream.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weird Dream, Lost A Shoe" /><published>2019-03-09T01:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-09T01:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/03/weird-dream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/03/weird-dream.html">&lt;p&gt;Last night, I had a weird dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dreamt that I was going to work and there was a building construction on going on the sidewalk. 
I had to climb up on something, like a pole or a very high bridge to pass through. 
Then my left shoe fell into a mud or a cement mix. I had no choice but to retrieve 
my shoe there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that I was not the only one who lost a shoe. 
There were also others that lost their shoe in the mud ( or cement mix.)
I tried to look for my left shoe but couldn’t find it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last night, I had a weird dream. I dreamt that I was going to work and there was a building construction on going on the sidewalk. I had to climb up on something, like a pole or a very high bridge to pass through. Then my left shoe fell into a mud or a cement mix. I had no choice but to retrieve my shoe there. I realized that I was not the only one who lost a shoe. There were also others that lost their shoe in the mud ( or cement mix.) I tried to look for my left shoe but couldn’t find it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End Of Week Journal Entry 3rdWeek Feb 2019</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/end-of-week-journal-3rdWeek-Feb-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End Of Week Journal Entry 3rdWeek Feb 2019" /><published>2019-02-18T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-02-18T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/end-of-week-journal-3rdWeek-Feb-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/end-of-week-journal-3rdWeek-Feb-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi, This is You From The Past!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want to tell you that ever since I played chess, I felt wonderful. 
It’s not about winning or losing. It’s about learning from mistakes, building
courage, making new friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to tell you that I feel wonderful to pursue this new job opportunity.
It will help you to learn more about Ruby On Rails. I hope you were able to 
get that job opportunity. Aja! You can do it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hi, This is You From The Past! I just want to tell you that ever since I played chess, I felt wonderful. It’s not about winning or losing. It’s about learning from mistakes, building courage, making new friends. I also want to tell you that I feel wonderful to pursue this new job opportunity. It will help you to learn more about Ruby On Rails. I hope you were able to get that job opportunity. Aja! You can do it!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Playing Chess Again</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/playing-chess-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Playing Chess Again" /><published>2019-02-18T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-02-18T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/playing-chess-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/playing-chess-again.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi, This is from your past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, Rad and I had an agreement to join the year-ender chess tournament. 
On the day of the tournament, I was not able to join. It’s because I was afraid to lose.
And also, it has been a very long long time since I played chess and so focused on practicing 
and studying positions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Feb 17, 2019, I decided to join this time to play. Rad was there with his son.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt wonderful to play again despite of not winning many games. I missed the feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am telling you, my future self, to pursue chess! It’s fun! It’s what you want since you 
were a kid.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hi, This is from your past. Last year, Rad and I had an agreement to join the year-ender chess tournament. On the day of the tournament, I was not able to join. It’s because I was afraid to lose. And also, it has been a very long long time since I played chess and so focused on practicing and studying positions. On Feb 17, 2019, I decided to join this time to play. Rad was there with his son. It felt wonderful to play again despite of not winning many games. I missed the feeling. I am telling you, my future self, to pursue chess! It’s fun! It’s what you want since you were a kid.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End Of Week Journal 2nd Week Feb 2019</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/end-of-week-journal-2ndWeek-Feb-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End Of Week Journal 2nd Week Feb 2019" /><published>2019-02-11T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/end-of-week-journal-2ndWeek-Feb-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/end-of-week-journal-2ndWeek-Feb-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, This is You From The Past!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this week, I want you to know that you have to be productive during weekends. 
If you remember, Jason Selk said in his book that the body tends to be at rest if 
it is not moving. In my understanding, if you don’t do anything productive, you
won’t be able to do anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I am encouraging you to start working on those personal projects you were working on.
There are so many things you can do and don’t waste your time. Be productive!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hello, This is You From The Past! For this week, I want you to know that you have to be productive during weekends. If you remember, Jason Selk said in his book that the body tends to be at rest if it is not moving. In my understanding, if you don’t do anything productive, you won’t be able to do anything. Now I am encouraging you to start working on those personal projects you were working on. There are so many things you can do and don’t waste your time. Be productive!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End Of Week Journal 1st Week Feb 2019</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/end-of-week-journal-1stWeekfeb2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End Of Week Journal 1st Week Feb 2019" /><published>2019-02-04T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-02-04T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/end-of-week-journal-1stWeekfeb2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/2019/02/end-of-week-journal-1stWeekfeb2019.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, This is You From The Past!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am blogging these incidents that happened during the week or even earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our guest came to our site office and caught one of our colleagues using 
his personal phone mostly during the day. I just learned later that this issue
was escalated to our manager in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;During the week, I was mostly busy figuring out this particular task I am working on.
Basically, we accept csv files from suppliers to parse and upload it on our database.
But this particular csv file contains lots of weird characters, weird values or garbled data.
I had to do testing the parsing of csv file and fix the logic and behavior until the
process totally works fine.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I reset my personal laptop to factory settings because the wifi adapter drivers are not functioning 
properly. When you encounter the error message saying “Error code 10”, that means that the drivers 
are corrupted and may need to download the drivers from the official site and install it again.
SO I did that and everything works again. But because the laptop is reset, all the software 
I had previously installed before are gone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hello, This is You From The Past! I am blogging these incidents that happened during the week or even earlier. Our guest came to our site office and caught one of our colleagues using his personal phone mostly during the day. I just learned later that this issue was escalated to our manager in the US. During the week, I was mostly busy figuring out this particular task I am working on. Basically, we accept csv files from suppliers to parse and upload it on our database. But this particular csv file contains lots of weird characters, weird values or garbled data. I had to do testing the parsing of csv file and fix the logic and behavior until the process totally works fine. I reset my personal laptop to factory settings because the wifi adapter drivers are not functioning properly. When you encounter the error message saying “Error code 10”, that means that the drivers are corrupted and may need to download the drivers from the official site and install it again. SO I did that and everything works again. But because the laptop is reset, all the software I had previously installed before are gone.</summary></entry></feed>